Antônio Ferreira

+55 (81) 98695-3988 antoniolfnt@outlook.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/antoniolfnt/ www.github.com/antoniolfnt

description:

Data Governance | Data Engineer

Information Technology Manager, certified in Scrum (SFPC) and Kanban (KEPC), dedicated to developing and learning about solutions for collecting, analyzing large data sets, creating and maintaining data pipelines and data structures. Currently, I am specializing in supporting all initiatives in delivering the data strategy, specifically activities related to Data Governance, Data Quality, Data Profiling, Agile Change Delivery, with some elements of Data Engineering, Data Architecture, Business Intelligence and Data Mining.

Main Skills

- Data Engineering
- Agile Methodologies
- Data Governance
- Project Management
- Data Mining
- Big Data

Work experience

Weduu (Full-time)

12/2022-Present

Data Governance / Data Engineer

Job

- Participate in and support the full project life cycle (initiation, planning, requirements, analysis, design, development, quality assurance, user-acceptance testing, deployment, and production support);

- Implement and maintain data policies and processes and provide ongoing monitoring and reporting on those processes;
- Designing, building and launching, reliable and scalable data quality architecture solutions for product evolution focusing on Data Analytics, Machine Learning and AI;
- Creation of data repositories for storage and integration of large volumes such as: Data Lakes, Data Ware Houses, Structured and Unstructured data.
- CRD Data (Part-time)

09/2022-Present

Data Project Manager (independent consultant)

Job Description:

- Troubleshoot and resolve product issues and concerns;
- Assisting customers face-to-face with any billing and/or equipment issues;
- Provide information about the data products and services;
- Seek and organize the implementation of the detected problem solutions.

Key projects / Task

- Instructor for the course "Beginner Data Analyst" for developers at the company;
- Management of developer allocation for projects;
- Creation of software requirements documentation;
- Conduct of meetings with investors.

MV Sistemas

09/2021-09/2022

Data Engineer | Business Intelligence Analyst

Job Description:

- Build, update and maintenance for ETL solutions on-premises using Pentaho, SQL, Python;
- Answering calls from customers for corrections of BI applications;
- Implementation of Business Intelligence architecture for new costumers;
- Development and maintenance of dashboards in: Qlik Sense and Tableau;
- Responsible for the definition, development and maintenance of the Data Quality Management methodology, principles and processes, as well as their documentation in terms of policies.

Kev Proiects / Tasks

- Creation of a new data product on-premises using Apache Airflow
- Active participation in meetings and discussions to promote a new architecture ETL for new customers:
- Planning the new ETL architecture on cloud using: Airflow, Spark, Docker, Python, Postgres and Oracle;
- Update of an old project using: Pentaho, SQL, and Postgres;
- Active in lectures to promote data quality and data governance all over the company.

Cidadão Fiscal

05/2020 - 09/2020

Data Analyst (Intern)

Job Description:

- Use of data analysis and artificial intelligence to monitor the spending of Pernambuco politicians;

- Improved format for displaying deputies' expenses for the population;
- Data extraction in the Transparency Portal and in the ALEPE portal, modeling, cleaning and transformation to assemble the Dashboards. (Power BI, Excel, Python).

Key projects / Tasks:

- Implementation and redesign of new website;
- Creation of a new data visualization template (Power BI) based on the new look of the ONG;
- More than 2T Data Management.

Education

- Faculdade Metropolitana Postgraduate degree (MBA) Data Mining 2023-2023
- University of Chicago Professional Education Artificial Intelligence and Data Science for Leaders – 2022–2022
- UNIFG Associate Degree Information Technology Management 2019-2021

Further Education & Certificates

- LGPD: Privacy Policy and Protection of Personal Data Udemy, 2023
- Data Governance, MDM and Data Quality with LGPD CS Treina, 2023
- Information Systems for the Management Faculdade Metropolitana, 2023
- COBIT 2019 Fundamentals ITXPRO, 2023
- Project Management Fundamentals Google, 2022
- Data Pipelines com Azure Stack Technology, 2022
- Certification Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (SFPC)
- Certification Kanban Essentials Professional Certificate (KEPC)
- Data Mining EAD Laureate, 2020
- Nano Course Business Intelligence (BI) FIAP, 2021

General Skills

Language Skills: Portuguese – Native | English – (B2).

Other skills: Data Governance, Data Quality, Data Lineage, Data Legislation and Security, Cobit 2019, DAMA DMBOOK, Data Engineering, Data Architecture, Data Management, Data Pipelines, Big Data, Data Mining, Data Science, Business Intelligence, Data Analytics, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Agile Methodologies (Scrum and Kanban).